hey everyone welcome back to our Channel
I am back with another interesting topic
in the tosa automation
playlist now continuing with our topic
test automation obstacles let's look at
our next obstacle which is called again
and again and again right now why is
this so in this particular obstacle we
need to complete uh the obstacle where
we need to click uh the following button
which is called click me and what will
happen is after a few clicks the button
will change its name to enough okay and
once this is done then uh you should
click that button finally to finish this
particular obstacle so let's try it out
here so I click here one twice Thrice
four times and after that it is enough
right right now you don't know how many
times you need to click uh in order for
this to be uh appearing right so it's
it's nothing fixed it is more Dynamic so
you have to put some logic through which
uh you can find out what's the name of
the button and when you should stop
clicking and when you should finally
click so that you can complete this
particular obstacle right so uh let's
see how we can uh complete this
particular obstacle uh in
tosa so coming back to our tosa
workspace as usual uh we are going to
scan this particular module so let's go
to our obstacles folder here go to scan
application and then um going to the
scan window uh the scanning is Prett
simple uh we just need to uh select this
particular button right and then um I'm
going to rename the
module and put the name here and save it
and close
this okay um now let's go back to our
test cases uh we'll be creating a new
obstacle
here uh a new test case with that
particular obstacle okay
and then uh we are going to add the
module back
here so let's try to search our module
here is the
module okay so the logic which we need
to implement here is we need to uh use a
looping object right now which Loop you
want to use uh completely depends on the
scenario but here uh it would be most
appropriate to use the while loop okay
because uh we have got a condition here
right so we are waiting for the name of
the button to change from something to
something else right so we have to Loop
uh until that change happens and then we
should stop okay so this is an ideal
case for a while loop so let's go ahead
and Implement that so when I right click
and I can say uh create while
statement okay and then uh I'm going to
drag this uh here because we want to do
this okay here we need to put or check
the condition um and then here I'm going
to change this to click button because
that's what we are going to do finally
once we check the name has changed to
enough okay so this is the final step
but uh we also need to put this under
the condition okay and what condition uh
we will do here let me change the name
here first so we'll say check button
okay and here instead of the click
operation uh we are going to do a
verification and uh here inside this we
are going to check for the inner text
and whether the inner text is equals
equals click
me okay so this is basically the initial
uh state of the button right so uh when
I refresh this page you will see the
initial name of the button is Click me
okay so I'm checking here uh whether
this particular button name is Click me
and if it is then I want to perform a
loop where I'll be clicking on this
button continuously until the name is
not equal to click me okay so what it
will do it will in the condition it will
check whether the button name is this if
it is yes then it will go into the loop
and it will click on that now this will
continue to happen
until this inner text uh changes to
something else and then uh this uh
condition will become false so it will
come out of the while loop okay and when
it comes out of the while loop uh at
that point of time we'll make our final
click okay uh which will basically
complete the obstacle right so it's a
pretty simple logic uh which you need to
implement uh and this is one way of
doing it there are many other ways of
doing this right so let's change the
work state to complete it and now we are
going to run this okay so let's see if
it
works so as you can see now it has
started uh clicking the button multiple
times and it will stop until uh it looks
for the inner text whiches uh changes to
enough and once it does then it will do
the final click and after that the
automation obstacle will be completed so
this is where you can some times use the
loop function uh which is available in
tosa either the do Loop or the Y Loop
you can also use the IFL statements
although these are not recommended ways
of um doing automation within TSA
because it's not a programming language
uh it's an automation tool but sometimes
uh if the situation guarantees that you
have to put some looping logic then uh
you can very well use uh the looping
objects which are available in tosa
that's all for this particular video if
you have any questions then please leave
it in the comments if you like this
video then please subscribe to our
Channel thanks for watching and I will
see you in the next video